<resources>
    <string name="app_name">health</string>
    <string name="underweight">"your Body Mass Index (BMI) is under 18.5, it's important to focus on both nutrition and exercise to gain weight in a healthy manner. Here are some recommendations:\n\n"
        <b>Nutrition\n</b>
        "1. Increase Caloric Intake:\n"
        "     *  Aim for calorie-dense foods that are nutritious.\n"
        "     *  Include healthy fats (avocados, nuts, seeds, \n          olive oil) and whole grains.\n\n"
        "2. Frequent Meals:\n"
        "     *  Eat 5-6 smaller meals throughout the day \n          instead of 2-3 large ones.\n\n"
        "3. Protein-Rich Foods:\n"
        "     *  Include lean meats, fish, eggs, dairy, legumes,\n          and plant-based proteins.\n"
        "     *  Consider protein shakes or smoothies.\n\n"
        "4. Healthy Snacks:\n"
        "     * Snack on nuts, nut butter, cheese, yogurt, and \n         dried fruits.\n\n"
        "5. Carbohydrates:\n"
        "    *  Whole grains like quinoa, brown rice, and whole \n         grain bread provide energy and nutrients.\n\n"
        "6 Stay Hydrated:\n"
        "    *  Drink fluids that provide calories, such as \n          smoothies or milk, rather than just water.\n\n"
        <b>Exercise\n</b>
        "1. Strength Training:\n"
        "       *Focus on resistance exercises (weights, bodyweight, \n          exercises) to build muscle mass.\n"
        "       *Aim for 2-3 sessions per week, targeting all major muscle\n           groups.\n\n"
        "2. Compound Exercises:\n"
        "       *Include exercises like squats, dead lifts, bench presses, \n          and rows, as they work multiple muscle groups.\n\n"
        "3. Limit Cardio:\n"
        "       *While cardiovascular exercise is important, excessive cardio \n           can burn calories that you need for weight gain.\n            Aim for moderate amounts.\n\n"
        "4. Consistency:\n"
        "       *Stay consistent with both your eating and exercise routines \n          for the best results.\n\n"
        "<b>Additional Tips</b>\n"
        "   *Consult a Healthcare Professional: Before making significant\n        changes to your diet or exercise routine, consider speaking\n     with a healthcare provider or a registered dietitian.\n"
        "   *Monitor Progress: Keep track of your weight and body\n     composition to see how your body responds to these    \n changes.";</string>

    <string name="healthy_weight_management_guide">
        "If your BMI falls within the range of 25.0–29.9, focusing on healthy weight management through balanced nutrition and regular exercise is essential. Here’s how to approach it with Ethiopian cuisine.\n\n"
        "             Nutrition with Ethiopian Foods:\n"
        "1.Portion Control:"
        "     Be mindful of portion sizes, especially with calorie-dense foods. Use smaller plates to help manage portions.\n"
        "2.Injera:"
        "     Use injera as a base but pair it with smaller portions of stews. Opt for whole grain or teff injera when possible.\n"
        "3.Legumes:"
        "      Prioritize dishes like misir wot (spicy lentil stew) and shiro (chickpea stew) for their high fiber and protein content, which can help keep you full.\n"
        "4.Vegetables:"
        "      Fill your plate with a variety of cooked or raw vegetables. Options like gomen (collard greens), tikil gomen (cabbage and carrots), and salads are nutritious and low in calories.\n"
        "5.Lean Proteins:"
        "      Choose lean proteins such as grilled chicken (like doro wot), fish, or plant-based proteins. Limit fatty cuts of meat and fried foods.\n"
        "6.Healthy Fats:"
        "     Use healthy fats like olive oil in moderation. Avocados and nuts are also good options but watch portion sizes.\n"
        "7.Limit Sugary Foods:"
        "     Reduce intake of sugary snacks and drinks. Opt for fresh fruits like bananas, mangoes, or oranges for sweetness.\n"
        "8.Stay Hydrated:"
        "     Drink plenty of water throughout the day. Herbal teas can also be a good option.\n\n"
        "             Best Exercises:\n"
        "1.Cardiovascular Exercise:"
        "     Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity cardio each week. Activities can include:\n"
        "     Brisk walking,"
        "     Cycling,"
        "     Swimming,"
        "     Dancing (including traditional Ethiopian dances).\n"
        "2.Strength Training:"
        "     Include strength training exercises at least 2-3 times a week:\n"
        "     Focus on major muscle groups with bodyweight exercises (squats, push-ups, lunges) or resistance bands.\n"
        "3.Flexibility and Balance:"
        "     Incorporate yoga or stretching routines to improve flexibility and balance, which can help prevent injuries.\n"
        "4.Active Lifestyle:"
        "     Look for ways to stay active throughout the day, such as walking more, taking the stairs, or engaging in community sports.\n\n"
        "            Additional Tips:\n"
        "Meal Planning:"
        "     Plan your meals to ensure you have healthy options available, reducing the temptation of unhealthy choices.\n"
        "Mindful Eating:"
        "     Practice mindful eating by savoring each bite and listening to your body's hunger cues.\n"
        "Seek Support:"
        "     Consider joining a community group or finding a workout buddy to stay motivated."
    </string>

    <string name="weight_loss_guide">
        "If your BMI is 30 or more, it's important to focus on a sustainable approach to weight loss through healthy nutrition and regular exercise. Here’s how to do this with an emphasis on Ethiopian cuisine.\n\n"
        <b>"          Nutrition with Ethiopian Foods:\n"</b>
        "1.Portion Control:\n"
        "     * Be mindful of portion sizes. Use smaller plates and bowls to help manage portions effectively.\n"
        "2.Injera:\n"
        "     * While injera is a staple, try to limit the quantity. Pair it with generous portions of vegetables and legumes.\n"
        "3.Legumes:\n"
        "     * Incorporate high-fiber dishes like misir wot (spicy lentil stew) and shiro (chickpea stew). They provide protein and keep you full.\n"
        "4.Vegetables:\n"
        "     * Fill your plate with a variety of vegetables. Options like gomen (collard greens), tikil gomen (cabbage and carrots), and salads are low in calories and high in nutrients.\n"
        "5.Lean Proteins:\n"
        "     * Choose lean sources of protein such as grilled chicken or fish. Limit red meat and avoid fried foods.\n"
        "6.Healthy Fats:\n"
        "     * Use healthy fats like olive oil in moderation. Nuts and seeds are good for snacks, but be mindful of portions.\n"
        "7.Limit Sugary Foods:\n"
        "    * Reduce intake of sweets, desserts, and sugary drinks. Opt for fresh fruits for natural sweetness.\n"
        "8.Hydration:\n"
        "    * Drink plenty of water throughout the day. Herbal teas are also good choices.\n\n"
        "<b>"         Best Exercises:\n"</b>
        "1.Cardiovascular Exercise:"
        "     * Aim for at least 150–300 minutes of moderate-intensity cardio each week. Consider activities such as:\n"
        "            *Walking (start with brisk walks),"
        "            * Swimming,"
        "            * Cycling, "
        "            *Dancing (including traditional Ethiopian dances).\n"
        "2.Strength Training:"
        "    * Include strength training at least 2-3 times a week:\n"
        "       *Focus on bodyweight exercises (squats, push-ups, lunges) and resistance bands to build muscle.\n"
        "3.Flexibility and Balance: "
        "    *Incorporate yoga or stretching routines to improve flexibility, balance, and reduce stress.\n"
        "4.Active Lifestyle: "
        "    *Look for ways to incorporate more movement into your day, like taking the stairs, gardening, or participating in community activities.\n\n"
        "<b>"       Additional Tips:\n"</b>
        "*Meal Planning:"
        "   * Prepare meals in advance to make healthier choices easier and reduce the temptation to eat out.\n"
        "*Mindful Eating:"
        "   * Practice mindful eating by focusing on your food, eating slowly, and listening to your body’s hunger cues.\n"
        "*Support System: "
        "   *Consider joining a support group or working with a healthcare professional or dietitian for guidance and motivation."
    </string>


</resources>